---
title: "WB Clerkship Exam 2019 Shift - 2 Mocktest"
subject: "WB Clerkship"
topic: "English Questions(30 Questions)"
questions:
  - question: "Fill in the blank with an appropriate preposition: He was successful ___ completing the job within four days."
    options:
      - "on"
      - "in"
      - "with"
      - "of"
    answer: "in"

  - question: "Find the word which has the same meaning as 'Commence'."
    options:
      - "Announce"
      - "Commend"
      - "Begin"
      - "Comment"
    answer: "Begin"

  - question: "Complete the idiom: When Deepak could not solve the problem he decided to give __."
    options:
      - "off"
      - "up"
      - "out"
      - "back"
    answer: "up"

  - question: "Replace the missing word: The man was so ___ that he believed that God Himself had drunk the milk offered."
    options:
      - "credible"
      - "creditable"
      - "credulous"
      - "incredible"
    answer: "credulous"

  - question: "Choose the correct form of the verb: He rushed to the hospital after he ___ the news."
    options:
      - "has heard"
      - "has been heard"
      - "has been hearing"
      - "had heard"
    answer: "had heard"

  - question: "Choose the correct indirect form of the sentence: He said to me, ‘I have never seen such a brilliant boy in my life’."
    options:
      - "That I have never seen such a brilliant boy in my life, he said to me."
      - "Such a brilliant boy was never seen in my life, he told me."
      - "The boy was so brilliant that he had never seen the like of him."
      - "He told me that he had never seen such a brilliant boy in his life."
    answer: "He told me that he had never seen such a brilliant boy in his life."

  - question: "Change from Passive to Active Voice: The crazy girl was laughed at."
    options:
      - "They laughed at the crazy girl."
      - "At the crazy girl they laughed."
      - "They were laughed at by the crazy girl."
      - "The crazy girl laughed at them."
    answer: "They laughed at the crazy girl."

  - question: "Find the word that means a plant that grows in hot-dry regions covered in spines but without leaves:"
    options:
      - "Creeper"
      - "Cactus"
      - "Eucalyptus"
      - "Sugarcane"
    answer: "Cactus"

  - question: "Find the opposite of ‘Attack’."
    options:
      - "fight"
      - "return"
      - "defend"
      - "pounce"
    answer: "defend"

  - question: "Find the word that means ‘Enormous’."
    options:
      - "Famous"
      - "Normal"
      - "Incongruous"
      - "Huge"
    answer: "Huge"

  - question: "Choose the most appropriate word to fill in the blank: A ___ is a person who gets things secretly and illegally into or out of a country."
    options:
      - "importer"
      - "criminal"
      - "smuggler"
      - "exporter"
    answer: "smuggler"

  - question: "Find the appropriate word that fits the underlined part of the sentence: The handkerchief was ___ into a bird by the magician."
    options:
      - "stuffed"
      - "put"
      - "transformed"
      - "puffed"
    answer: "transformed"

  - question: "He was too preoccupied ___ his studies to think of other matters."
    options:
      - "with"
      - "in"
      - "at"
      - "on"
    answer: "with"

  - question: "Change from Active to Passive Voice: The boys are flying kites in the sky."
    options:
      - "Kites are flying in the sky by the boys."
      - "In the sky, kites are flown by the boys."
      - "Kites are being flown by the boys in the sky."
      - "The flying of kites in the sky is done by the boys."
    answer: "Kites are being flown by the boys in the sky."

  - question: "Fill in the blank with an appropriate preposition: The tired hawker sat ___ the tree."
    options:
      - "up"
      - "in"
      - "from"
      - "under"
    answer: "under"

  - question: "Fill in the blank with an appropriate preposition: Sita and Meera quarrelled ___ themselves."
    options:
      - "among"
      - "between"
      - "with"
      - "for"
    answer: "with"

  - question: "Replace the underlined verb with the most appropriate phrasal verb: He decided to ___ him at his home."
    options:
      - "Call for"
      - "Call on"
      - "Call up"
      - "Call off"
    answer: "Call on"

  - question: "Fill in the blank with an appropriate preposition: Ram was good ___ Chemistry."
    options:
      - "at"
      - "with"
      - "about"
      - "over"
    answer: "at"

  - question: "Change the following statement into an interrogative sentence: You have had your dinner."
    options:
      - "Had you have your dinner?"
      - "Have you had your dinner?"
      - "What about your dinner, did you have it?"
      - "Did you have your dinner?"
    answer: "Have you had your dinner?"

  - question: "Fill in the blank with an appropriate preposition: Rita’s mother did not approve ___ her returning home so late at night."
    options:
      - "for"
      - "on"
      - "to"
      - "of"
    answer: "of"

  - question: "Fill in the blank with an appropriate word: Neither Lata nor Sujata ___ present in class on 14th October."
    options:
      - "were"
      - "are"
      - "was"
      - "have been"
    answer: "was"

  - question: "Replace the missing word with the right word: All Alok ___ were present during the meeting."
    options:
      - "except"
      - "expect"
      - "exceed"
      - "accept"
    answer: "except"

  - question: "Choose the correct spelling:"
    options:
      - "Exaggerate"
      - "Exagarate"
      - "Exaggarate"
      - "Exagerate"
    answer: "Exaggerate"

  - question: "Find the word that means 'Essential':"
    options:
      - "Unimportant"
      - "Irrelevant"
      - "Essence"
      - "Vital"
    answer: "Vital"

  - question: "Complete the idiom: The old lady was murdered in cold ___."
    options:
      - "ice"
      - "water"
      - "blood"
      - "milk"
    answer: "blood"

  - question: "Fill in the blank with an appropriate preposition: The policeman seized him ___ his arm and led him away."
    options:
      - "by"
      - "with"
      - "at"
      - "on"
    answer: "by"

  - question: "Choose the correct spelling:"
    options:
      - "Hyphanated"
      - "Hyphennated"
      - "Hyphannated"
      - "Hyphenated"
    answer: "Hyphenated"

  - question: "Complete the idiom: His old shoes have stood him in good ___ in his travels."
    options:
      - "stead"
      - "years"
      - "price"
      - "manner"
    answer: "stead"

  - question: "Choose the most appropriate word to fill in the blank: The examiner could not understand the candidate’s handwriting because it was ___."
    options:
      - "distinct"
      - "shining"
      - "stylish"
      - "illegible"
    answer: "illegible"

  - question: "Replace the underlined word with the right alternative: The time allowed for the work should have been ___."
    options:
      - "indefinite"
      - "subsequent"
      - "efficient"
      - "sufficient"
    answer: "sufficient"

---